{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Secretary Thaddeus Ross","incorrectAnswers":["Nick Fury","Quentin Beck","Vision"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by William Hurt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tilda Swinton","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Ruby Dee","Saoirse Ronan"],"question":"Who won the 2007 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Karen Crowder in Michael Clayton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"For example","incorrectAnswers":["And another thing","In other words","And so on"],"question":"What does the Latin abbreviation term 'e.g.' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Distance","incorrectAnswers":["Time","Pressure","Magnetism"],"question":" What does a micron measure?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Face Off","incorrectAnswers":["Drop Puck","Toss Up","Throw Down"],"question":"In hockey, what is the equivalent of a rugby scrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Qatar","United Arab Emirates","Kuwait"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Bahrain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Leon Trotsky","incorrectAnswers":["Che Guevara","Nikita Khrushchev","Fidel Castro"],"question":"Who did Stalin allegedly force Norway to expel in 1936 by buying its entire herring catch?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vertigo","incorrectAnswers":["Apocalypse Now","The Sixth Sense","Inside Out"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A former detective becomes obsessed with the woman he has been hired to trail.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Lion, the Witch, and the Wardrobe'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","China","Australia"],"question":"From Which Country Does The Poinsettia Plant Originate","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"5000","incorrectAnswers":["1000","10000","20000"],"question":"Roughly How Many Men Were There In A Roman Legion?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Belarus","Canada","Sierra Leone"],"question":"Caracas is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Travolta","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Michael Douglas"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Pulp Fiction and The Thin Red Line?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"24th December","incorrectAnswers":["25th December","26th December","31st December"],"question":"The Nordic countries (Denmark, Sweden, Norway notably) tend to celebrate Christmas chiefly on which date?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Mock Turtle","incorrectAnswers":["Humpty Dumpty","Tweedledee","Dodo"],"question":"In Alice In Wonderland, who never stopped sobbing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tallinn","incorrectAnswers":["Copenhagen","Paris","Zürich"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Estonia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Graceland","incorrectAnswers":["Traceland","Faceland","Placeland"],"question":"Which Paul Simon Album Won A Grammy For Album Of The Year In 1987?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Samuel Beckett","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Nikolai Gogol","Jonathan Swift"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Waiting for Godot'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hemoglobin","incorrectAnswers":["Histone","Histidin","GABA"],"question":"What protein is resposible for carrying oxygen in our blood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Algae","incorrectAnswers":["Bacteria","Viruses","Moss"],"question":"What is Phycology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kyiv","incorrectAnswers":["Minsk","Nur Sultan","Karachi"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Ukraine?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ghana","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Ivory Coast","São Tomé and Príncipe"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Togo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Corduroy","incorrectAnswers":["Chardonnay","Cordon Bleu","Cordon Sanitaire"],"question":"What is the name of the durable cotton fabric derived from the French for \"Cord fit for the King\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"OUTATIME","incorrectAnswers":["GOINBACK","SEEYAL8R","NOROADS"],"question":"What was the license plate on the Delorean in Back To The Future?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rusty Cage","incorrectAnswers":["Where Is My Mind","Cocaine","Woodstock"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by Soundgarden and was later covered by Johnny Cash?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I wish I knew how to quit you.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I want to be alone.\"","\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","\"Show me the money!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Brokeback Mountain'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Helsinki","incorrectAnswers":["Suva","Tarawa","Copenhagen"],"question":"What is the capital city of Finland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"I Want Candy","incorrectAnswers":["Louie Louie","Cocaine","Mad World"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by The Strangeloves and was later covered by Bow Wow Wow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'SOS'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Gymnastics","Cycling","Swimming"],"question":"With which sport is Rafael Nadal associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Electroconvulsive Therapy","incorrectAnswers":["Endrine Cardio Therapy","Endless Carotid Tears","Environmental Combined Theatre"],"question":"What Does E C T Stand For","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Two Towers","incorrectAnswers":["Life, the Universe and Everything","The Mysterious Island","A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Aragorn sped on up the hill.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A weatherman finds himself trapped in a small town as he lives the same day over and over again.","incorrectAnswers":["A young F.B.I. cadet must receive the help of a cannibal to help catch another serial killer.","A thief who steals secrets through dreams must plant an idea into the mind of a C.E.O.","Historical events unfold from the perspective of an Alabama man with an IQ of 75."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Groundhog Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Status Quo","incorrectAnswers":["Saxon","Pulp","Rudimental"],"question":"Who Recorded The Albums \"In The Army Now\" And \"Whatever You Want\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burkina Faso","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Mali","Togo"],"question":"Ouagadougou is the capital of ______?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mark Spitz","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Phelps","Ian Thorpe","Matt Biondi"],"question":"Who Won 7 gold Medals In Swimming At The 1972 Olympics?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ferdinand Marcos","incorrectAnswers":["Luis Fernandez","Julio Cruz","Terab Loquito"],"question":"Who Was Ousted As President of the Philippines By Corazon Aquino In 1986?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shaggy","incorrectAnswers":["Messy","Patchy","Tangled"],"question":"Which is the name of Scooby Doo's best friend?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Hampshire","incorrectAnswers":["Washington","Oregon","Texas"],"question":"In which US state is Mount Washington?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Add 273.15","incorrectAnswers":["Add 100","Multiply by 3.14","Subtract 32"],"question":"What do you have to do to convert a Kelvin temperature to Celsius?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Indonesia","Philippines"],"question":"In which country is Lake Taupo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Uralic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Hindi' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Slayer","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American thrash metal band released the studio album 'Reign in Blood'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Magpies","incorrectAnswers":["The Whites","The Hoops","The Citizens"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Newcastle United?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Internet Relay Chat","incorrectAnswers":["Information Rating Center","International Rotator Cuff","Institute of Remote Clients"],"question":"In computing, what do the initials IRC mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2011","incorrectAnswers":["2009","2018","2001"],"question":"In what year did a tsunami trigger the Fukushima nuclear disaster?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Elephant","incorrectAnswers":["Penguin","Eagle","Peacock"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Evernote logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Toadstool","incorrectAnswers":["Spider","Coral","Cloud"],"question":"What is a death cap? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Rude Boy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Francis Ford Coppola","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Godfather?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Ramat Gan","Petah Tikva","Beersheba"],"question":"In which city is the Wailing Wall","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Orlando Magic","incorrectAnswers":["Orlando Colts","Orlando Timbers","Orlando Raptors"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Orlando?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard Nixon","incorrectAnswers":["James Polk","Abraham Lincoln ","Harry S. Truman"],"question":"Who was the 37th president of the USA, in term during the period 1969–1974?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Miracle Worker","incorrectAnswers":["A Raisin in the Sun","The Glass Menagerie","Death of a Salesman"],"question":"What play, set in Tuscumbia, Alabama and at the Perkins Institute for the blind, tells the story of Helen Keller's life?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Discombobulate","incorrectAnswers":["Cacophony","Dragoman","Dragoman"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to disconcert of confuse'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nova Scotia","incorrectAnswers":["Quebec","Labrador","Alberta"],"question":"Halifax is the capital of which Canadian province?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Oliver Twist'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Turkey","Belgium"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Delphi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Stringed","Percussion","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a clarinet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"He bit off an opponent's ear","incorrectAnswers":["He was found to be doping","He had cocaine detected during a drugs test","Match fixing"],"question":"Why was Mike Tyson fined $3 million by the boxing association in 1997?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Atlantic","incorrectAnswers":["Pacific","Indian","Arctic"],"question":"What is the second largest ocean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Suprematism","incorrectAnswers":["Cubism","Dadaism","Impressionism"],"question":"Which art movement is characterized by flat geometric shapes on plain backgrounds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lead","incorrectAnswers":["Copper","Aluminum","Iron"],"question":"What is the best metal to use as a thick shield to block gamma rays produced by nuclear fission?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"1997","incorrectAnswers":["1993","2001","1989"],"question":"In which year was the first Harry Potter book released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Annabel Lee'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Little worms","incorrectAnswers":["Skinny Fingers","Slim Pencils","Long Legs"],"question":"Vermicelli literally means ___________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Washington Irving","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Rip Van Winkle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"12","incorrectAnswers":["8","10","4"],"question":"How many avenues radiate from the Arc de Triomphe in Paris?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Black Eyed Peas ","incorrectAnswers":["NWA","Backstreet Boys","*NSync"],"question":"Which music act includes MC Taboo and will.i.am in their line up?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Figure skating","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Rugby Union","Motor Racing"],"question":"With which sport is Sonja Henie associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Jurassic Period","incorrectAnswers":["The Thoracic Period","The Mezozoic Period","The Triambic Period"],"question":"Which Period Came Between The Triassic & Cretaceous Periods?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chinatown","incorrectAnswers":["The Terminator","Ghost","Breakfast at Tiffany's"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Jake Gittes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Volleyball","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Golf","Rugby Union"],"question":"With which sport is Karch Kiraly associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Arab Emirates","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Saudi Arabia","Pakistan"],"question":"Abu Dhabi is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"viruses","incorrectAnswers":["bacteria","fungi","parasites"],"question":"Interferons are proteins produced by the human body to interfere with the spread of what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Seismometer","incorrectAnswers":["Ceilometer","Graphometer","Spectrometer"],"question":"Which device measures the strength of an earthquake?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"It Was Sold To The United States","incorrectAnswers":["It had the most deadly volcanic eruption in history","The first recorded meteor impact","It declared independence"],"question":"What Happened To Alaska In 1867?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The minotaur","incorrectAnswers":["The centaur","The gorgon","The chimera"],"question":"In Greek mythology, what kind of monster is an offspring of a woman and a bull?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Eight","Black"],"question":"In Portuguese, what is the meaning of the word 'vermelho'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Dickens","Gabriel Garcia Marquez","Washington Irving"],"question":"Who wrote \"1984\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Craig","George Lazenby","Sean Connery"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in A View to a Kill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C.S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["J.R.R. Tolkien","J.K. Rowling","Roald Dahl"],"question":"Which author wrote the 7 \"Chronicles of Narnia\" novels, which were published between 1950 and 1956?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'No Line on the Horizon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Medal of Honor","incorrectAnswers":["Purple Heart","Bronze Star","Silver Star"],"question":"What is the name of the US Military's highest award for valor in combat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mangroves","incorrectAnswers":["Bogs","Trobans","Savanna"],"question":"What is the name for dense sea-water swamps along coasts of hot countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Yanka Kupala","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Vladimir Nabokov","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Heritage'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Parchment paper","incorrectAnswers":["Newspaper","Rice paper","Wrapping paper"],"question":"What type of paper do you need to cook fish en papillote, in order to seal in the flavor and juices?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"BTS","incorrectAnswers":["Kara","2NE1","Red Velvet"],"question":"Which South Korean boy group released the single 'Dynamite'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles II","incorrectAnswers":["Henry VIII","James II","Elizabeth I"],"question":"During Which King's Reign Did The Great Fire Of London Occur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Koreanic","Austronesian","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Marathi' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Grandmaster","incorrectAnswers":["J. Jonah Jameson","Dr. Bruce Banner","Ivan Vanko"],"question":"Jeff Goldblum plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Val Kilmer","incorrectAnswers":["Kevin Spacey","Tom Cruise","Samuel L. Jackson"],"question":"Which actor has played Jim Morrison, Elvis Presley, and Batman in various films?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hound of the Baskervilles","incorrectAnswers":["The A.B.C. Murders","The Da Vinci Code","The Murder of Roger Ackroyd"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Mr. Sherlock Holmes, who was usually very late in the mornings, save upon those not infrequent occasions when he stayed up all night, was seated at the breakfast table.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Caracas","incorrectAnswers":["Panama City","Recife","Cali"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Venezuela?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mexico City","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Buenos Aires","Rome"],"question":"Which world capital is home to Plaza de Garibaldi, near the Avenida Juarez?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Panama Canal","incorrectAnswers":["The Suez Canal","The Erie Canal","The Gulf Intracoastal Waterway"],"question":"What is the name of the 50-mile waterway that stretches from Limon Bay on the Caribbean to the Bridge of the Americas on the Pacific Ocean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Canis rufus","incorrectAnswers":["Canis lupus","Canis latrans","Canis aureus"],"question":"What is the scientific name for the red wolf?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"easy"},